Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW) Local 2110 Archived Website, Oct 13, 2013-ongoing; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110 (New York, N.Y.)
  The Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW Local 2110) is the union for graduate employees at New York University (NYU) and the Polytechnic Institute of New York University. This includes teaching assistants, research assistants, and graduate assistants. The Polytechnic Institute organizes science and engineering graduate students. The union was established in 1998 and negotiated their first contract with NYU in 2002. In 2004, the National Labor Relations Board reversed the Brown University decision, declaring private universities are not required to bargain with graduate employees and leading to NYU not negotiating a new contract. Over the next years, GSOC continued the fight for recognition at NYU, and currently gathering signatures to get NYU to negotiate a contract restoring healthcare benefits. The website contains information about the union and its Polytechnic Institute affiliate (SET-UAW), campaigns, news, and event listings.
  Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096 Archived Website, Mar 1, 2013 - ongoing; Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096
  The Independent Association of Publishers' Employees Inc. (IAPE) was founded 1937 by a group of Dow Jones & Company employees in Manhattan, NY. It has grown to represent employees at various parts of Dow Jones & Company in many locations across the North American continent. In 1997, by vote of the membership, IAPE became Local 1096 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA). Subsequently, IAPE joined The Newspaper Guild sector of the CWA by action of the Board of Directors. The website contains bylaws, grievances, benefits, budgets, their contract, meeting minutes, and news.
  Newspaper employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 Archived Website, Feb 8, 2009 - ongoing; International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the United States and Canada. Local 52 (New York, N.Y.)
  International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 was founded in the early 1920s, and was officially chartered by the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) in 1924. The local's jurisdiction includes, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Pennsylvania (with the exception of Pittsburgh), and Connecticut. The labor union represents technicians, artisans and craftspeople in the entertainment industry, including live theatre, motion picture and television production, and trade shows. The website includes information on films and television series currently being filmed in the local's jurisdiction, membership applications, links and other resources.
  Theaters |x Employees |X Labor unions |z United States.
- International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services Archived Website, Nov 1, 2013-ongoing; International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services
  International Association of Women in Fire & Emergency Service (iWomen) is descended from Women in the Fire Service (WFS), Inc., which began in 1982. In September 2007, WFS merged with the Women Chief Fire Officers (WCFO) to form the International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services (iWomen). iWomen supports, mentors, and educates current and future women in the fire and emergency services. The website includes a photo gallery, news and job postings, position statements, reports, guidelines and procedures, and other information about the association.
  Women fire fighters -- United States.; Women -- Employment -- United States.; Women in the Fire Service (Organization)
- International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Painters District Council 9 of New York City. Archived Website, May 3, 2009 - ongoing; International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Painters District Council 9 of New York City
  The District Council 9 New York is local branch of the International Union of Painters and Allied Trades, chartered in 1900. District Council 9 is an organization of painters, decorators, wall covers, drywall finishers, sign painters, metal polishers, bridge & structural steel painters, civil service painters, lead abatement workers, glaziers & architectural metal glassworkers, paint makers, paint makers and allied trades. The website contains information on their apprencticeship programs, news, and event listings.
  Painters, Industrial -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.
- International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers (BAC) Archived Website, Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing; International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers
  Bricklayers and Allied Craftsworkers (BAC) Local 7, established in 1994, was formed from seven BAC locals. Local 7, and is part of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers which, represents craftworkers in the trowel trades. BAC Local 7 represents workers in the New York and New Jersey area.
- International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey) Archived Website, May 3, 2009 - ongoing; International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers. Local 7 (New York, N.Y.)
  Founded in 1865, the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers represents craftworkers in the trowel trades across the United States and Canada including bricklayers, stone and marble masons, cement masons, plasterers, tilesetters, terrazzo and mosaic workers, and pointers/cleaners/caulkers. The website contains contracts, training and organizing programs, benefit programs, and event listings.
  Bricklayers -- Labor unions; Bricklayers -- Labor unions
- International Union of Elevator Constructors (IUEC) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; International Union of Elevator Constructors
  The International Union of Elevator Constructors (IUEC) is a trade union in the United States and Canada of individuals who construct, modernize, repair, and service elevators, escalators, moving walkways, and other conveyances. The IUEC claims a membership of over 25,000 and was founded in 1901.
  Elevator constructor
- International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, UAW Archived Website, Jan 15, 2010 - ongoing; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America
  The International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America also known as the United Auto Workers (UAW), founded in 1935, is a trade union that represents workplaces ranging from multinational corporations, small manufacturers and state and local governments to colleges and universities, hospitals and private non-profit organizations. UAW members work in industries as diverse as automobile and parts manufacturing, health care, casino gaming and higher education. The UAW has more than 750 local unions, with 390,000 active members and more than 600,000 retired members in the United States, Canada and Puerto Rico.
  Automobile industry workers |z United States.
- Jewish Labor Committee Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.)
  The Jewish Labor Committee, an independent secular organization, is the voice of the Jewish community in the labor movement and the voice of the labor movement in the Jewish community. The JLC was formed in 1934 by Yiddish-speaking immigrant trade union leaders and leaders of such groups as the Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring, the Jewish Labor Bund, and the United Hebrew Trades, in response to the rise of Nazism in Germany. The JLC enables the Jewish community and the trade union movement to work together on important issues of shared interest and concern, in pursuit of economic and social justice. The website contains activity reports, news listings, and information on chapters.
  Anti-fascist movements -- United States.; Jews -- United States -- Societies, etc.; Jewish labor unions |z United States.
- Jobs With Justice Archived Website, Sep 26, 2007 - ongoing; Jobs With Justice
  Jobs with Justice, founded in 1987, is a national network of local coalitions that bring together labor unions, faith groups, community organizations, and student activists who fight for working people through long-term multi-issue coalition building, grassroots base-building, organizing, and strategic militant action. Jobs with Justice coalitions also worked on 127 community campaigns on issues like jobs and the economy, health care, immigrants' rights, global justice, accountable development, and sweat-free ordinances.
  Community organization |z United States.; Social justice -- United States.; Employment |z United States.; Working class -- Social conditions -- United States.; Unemployment |z United States.
- Labor and Working Class History Association Archived Website, Oct 15, 2009 - ongoing; Labor and Working-Class History Association
  The Labor and Working Class History Association (LAWCHA) is an organization of historians, labor educations, and working class activists who seek to promote public and scholarly awareness of labor and working class history through research, writing, and organizing. The organization also promotes labor and working class history put into history and social studies curricula in public schools, colleges, and universities. LAWCHA gives grants and prizes to graduate students. The LAWCHA also publishes the journal, Labor: Studies in Working-Class History of the Americas.
  Working class |z United States |x History; Labor unions -- United States -- History; Labor unions -- United States -- History; Labor |z United States |x History.; Labor |z United States |x History.; Labor movement -- United States -- History; Labor movement -- United States -- History
- Manumit School (1924-1957) Archived Website, Sep 2, 2009 - ongoing; Manumit Association
  The Manumit School was an experimental boarding school in Pawling NY. Founded on purchased farm land in 1924 by William and Helen Fincke, it was formally call the Manumit School for Workers' Children. An early promotional flyer for the school asked parents if they'd like their children to grow up "to become men and women who can think for themselves, stand on their own two feet and fight injustice and oppression. " It's teachings were meant to provide a "progressive " "workers education" slant during a time of increasing socialist optimism in America. In 1944 the school moved to Bensalem Township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania. The school closed in 1957. This website is an informational website.
  Progressive education |z New York (State).; Working class -- Education -- New York (State)
- National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians Archived Website, Mar 15, 2009 - ongoing; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians
  National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians-Communications Workers of America (NABET-CWA), founded in 1934, is a Union of workers who are employed in the broadcasting, distributing, telecasting, recording, cable, video, sound recording and related industries in North America. NABET-CWA has contracts with ABC, NBC, FOX and other networks, as well as local TV stations across the country and members include engineers, photographers, editors, directors, technicians, graphic artists, traffic coordinators, clerical workers, truck operators, writers, reporters, anchors, producers and others in the television and cable industry. The website includes news and event listings, their newsletters, training materials, and audiovisual materials.
- National Domestic Workers Alliance Archived Website, Oct 26, 2011 - ongoing; The National Domestic Workers Alliance
  Founded in 2007, the National Domestic Workers Alliance organizes domestic workers in the United States to improve their living and working conditions, win respect and justice from employers and government for exploited domestic workers; challenge racism and sexism; end the exclusion of domestic workers from recognition and protection; and build a movement of migrant workers to fight the labor displacement and exploitation created by globalization.
  Household employees -- United States
- National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320 Archived Website, Jan 29, 2009 - ongoing; National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320
  The National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320, represents the majority of those who work in federally-funded legal services programs across the United States. The local also represents workers in other types of law offices, various human services programs and other agencies. The website includes new listings, strike listings, meeting information, and other information.
  Legal services |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- National Writers Union Archived Website, Dec 8, 2012 - ongoing; National Writers Union, Local 1981
  The National Writers Union (NWU) represents freelance writers throughout the United States. It was formed in 1981 during the Writers' Congress held in New York City. In 1981, the NWU affiliated with the United Auto Workers (UAW) as Local 1981. As of 2011, the NWU has over 1,500 members in fifteen locals. The website contains news and chapter information.
  Authors |x Labor unions.
- New York Building Congress Archived Website, Mar 14, 2009 - ongoing; New York Building Congress
  The New York Building Congress, founded in 1921, is a coalition of 400 constituent organizations comprising more than 250,000 skilled trades people and professionals that works to advance economic and infrastructure investment and job creation. The Congress publishes reports and analysis related to building projects in New York City. The Congress also created the New York Building Foundation, which promotes research, education, and philanthropy in the construction industry. The website contains reports, committee and council information, and event listings.
  Construction industry -- New York (State) -- New York.; Building trades -- New York (State) -- New York; Labor-management committees -- New York (State) -- New York.
- New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health Archived Website, Apr 16, 2009 - ongoing; New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health
  New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH), founded in 1980, is a non-profit coalition of 200 local unions and more than 400 individual workers, physicians, lawyers and other health and safety activists dedicated to the right of worker safety on the job. NYCOSH operates throughout New York City, Long Island and the Lower Hudson Valley. The website gives information and assistance for those injured on the job and other training and safety resources.
  Industrial hygiene -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrial safety -- New York (State) -- New York
- New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Archived Website, Mar 14, 2009 - ongoing; New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council
  Founded in the 1930s, The New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council, AFL-CIO (Hotel Trades Council), is the union of hotel workers in New York City. The Council represents approximately 30,000 non-managerial employees working in all hotel departments, including: housekeeping, public space, dining room, banquet, room service, kitchen, stewarding, bar, mini-bar, audio-visual, front desk, reservations, PBX, bell and door services, concierge, night auditing, laundry, valet, engineering, maintenance, electrical, carpentry, painting, upholstery, business centers, night cleaning, health spas, security, garage, purchasing and receiving, and storeroom in over 300 hotels in the New York City area. It is affiliated with the SEIU, UNITE-HERE, OPEIU, IUOE, IBEW, IUPAT, and USWA.
  Central labor councils.; Hospitality industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- New York Labor History Association Archived Website, May 1, 2009 - ongoing; New York Labor History Association
  New York Labor History Association (NYLHA) was founded in 1976 by trade unionists, academics, students, archivists, educators, labor editors, attorneys, and retirees, mostly from New York State. NYLHA encourages the study of workers and their organizations and serves as a bridge between past and present labor unionists and academics. The website includes news and event listings, labor history resources, and prize winners.
  Labor |z New York (State) |x History |x Societies, etc.
- New York Metro Area Postal Workers Union, Local 10, Nov 1, 2013-ongoing; National Federation of Post Office Clerks. Local 10 (New York, N.Y.)
  The New York Metro Area Postal Union (American Postal Workers Union, Local 10) represents clerks, motor vehicle staff, maintenance workers and mail-handlers in the greater New York City area. In 1973 the union changed its name to the New York Metro Area Postal Union, from the Postal Union of Manhattan-Bronx Clerks, the new name reflecting the inclusion of the New York Bulk and Foreign Mail Center and the North Jersey Facility in the local's bargaining unit. The website contains news listings, their health plan, agreements, and other materials.
- New York State AFL-CIO Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; New York State AFL-CIO
  The New York State AFL-CIO, in 1958, is the federation of labor unions in New York State affiliated with the AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations). The New York State AFL-CIO, in 1958, is the federation of labor unions in New York State affiliated with the AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations). The website contains information on their legislative action campaigns, press releases, regional and state news, endorsements, council members and other councils, and event listings.
- New York Taxi Workers Alliance Archived Website, May 6, 2011 - ongoing; New York Taxi Workers Alliance
  New York Taxi Workers Alliance, founded in 1998, consists of 15,000 members of yellow taxicab drivers. NYTWA provides legal, health and financial services and improve working conditions through organizing, political and media advocacy, litigation, direct legal services, and access to healthcare. They are part of the Central Labor Council and the International Taxi Workers Alliance. The website contains information on current campaigns, membership information, press releases, event listings, and a blog.
  Taxicab workers |z New York (State) |z New York.; Taxicab workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Newspaper Guild of New York, CWA Local 31003 Archived Website, Feb 5, 2009 - ongoing; Newspaper Guild of New York
  The Newspaper Guild of New York, launched in 1934, is an labor union for people in the news and media business, including print, photo, video, and digital journalists, as well as employees in advertising, circulation and other related areas. They represent about 3,000 employees at New York area-based media organizations and their respective bureaus around the nation.
  Newspaper employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Reporters and reporting -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Organization of Staff Analysts Archived Website, Feb 9, 2013 - ongoing; Organization of Staff Analysts
  Founded in 1970 by twelve employees of the New York City Department of Personnel as the Committee of Personnel Examiners, the Organization of Staff Analysts (OSA) became the official collective bargaining agent for Analysts in the Board of Education in 1985. OSA is a member of, and bargains collectively through, the Municipal Labor Committee. It represents employees of the City of New York in the Analyst title series serving in more than fifty city agencies. The website contains information on benefits, newsletter, and weekly newsline.
  Government employee unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Civil service -- New York (State) -- New York.; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Collective bargaining |x Government employees |z New York (State) |z New York
- Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York. Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York
  The Professional Staff Congress is the union that represents more than 20,000 faculty and staff at the City University of New York (CUNY). The union negotiates, administers and enforces collective bargaining agreements; protects the rights of staff through the grievance and arbitration process; engages in political activity on behalf of CUNY and its staff and students; and advocates for the interests of the instructional staff in various forums. It is affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT), the American Association of University Professors (AAUP), the New York State United Teachers (NYSUT), and the NYC Central Labor Council (CLC).
  College teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Radicals at Work Archived Website, Apr 1, 2011 - Sep 30, 2014; Radicals at Work
  Radicals at Work is a network of young activists and radicals involved in workers' movements. The network works to build a stronger movement from the bottom-up. The website informs and educates on issues in the workers' movement. The website has not been updated since mid-2010.
  Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.; Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.
- Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Archived Website, Mar 17, 2009 - ongoing; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.)
  Local 1-S is a local branch of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union/UFCW (RWDSU), which represents Macy's workers in the United States and 3,500 employees at the Macy's department store in Herald Square, Manhattan. The union works to protect Macy's employees' right to the fair wages and benefits that allow them to support themselves and their families. The website contains news, benefits information, contracts, and images.
  Service industries |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Department stores |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website, Nov 6, 2013-ongoing; Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)
  Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU/UFCW), Local 3, founded in 1937, represents more than 2,000 sales clerks, shelf stockers and clerical workers at Bloomingdale's flagship 59th Street store in New York City, with extended protection to workers at the Bloomingdale's SoHo store. The website contains news and event listings, meeting minutes, contract information, and newsletters.
  Department stores |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Service industries |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- SAG-AFTRA Archived Website, Feb 25, 2012 - ongoing; SAG-AFTRA (Organization)